<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sparkplug - Your software development partners</title>
    <description>Sparkplug works with organizations to build great software through human-centered design and fervent execution. We are your software development partners.</description>
    <link>http://sparkpl.ug/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sparkpl.ug/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Giving back to celebrate Two Years!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is Sparkplug’s 2nd birthday and we are ready to celebrate! We intend to do this with our local community of digital natives and wanderers. The wonderful  group of writers, bloggers, photographers and small businesses. You furnish us with useful and anecdotal information. Now it’s time for us to help you be your best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many bloggers, photographers and Twitterati have a lot to say and share with us. We have noticed, however, that many lack a solid online presence and portfolio. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of original local content littered all over Blogger, Google Plus, Wordpress.com among others. Too much clutter, poor SEO, and not the best looking websites. We seek to change this.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also wish to give back to the micro, small and medium enterprises and non-profit organizations. We hope to do this by building beautiful, clean websites that reflect the essence of your work and programs while allowing organizational character, culture and ethos to shine through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introducing the blogger, photographer and SME bundles: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pricing&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;row plans&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;plan&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;price&quot;&gt;UGX 1&lt;span class=&quot;per&quot;&gt;M&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;h5&gt;Blogger&lt;/h5&gt;
                    &lt;ul class=&quot;list-unstyled features&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Custom Domain&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Beautiful publishing platform &lt;span class=&quot;per-minute&quot;&gt;web and mobile on the move&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Responsive Website&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Focus on Readability&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Free hosting for 1 year&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Tech support for 1 year&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;
                      &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ray@sparkpl.ug?subject=Sparkplug Blogger Offer&quot; class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;Claim&lt;/a&gt;
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;plan&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;price&quot;&gt;UGX 1&lt;span class=&quot;per&quot;&gt;M&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;h5&gt;Photographer&lt;/h5&gt;
                    &lt;ul class=&quot;list-unstyled features&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Custom Domain&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Beautiful publishing platform &lt;span class=&quot;per-minute&quot;&gt;custom gallery settings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Responsive Website&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;High Definition Support&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Free hosting for 1 year&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Tech support for 1 year&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;
                      &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ray@sparkpl.ug?subject=Sparkplug Photographer Offer&quot; class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;Claim&lt;/a&gt;
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;plan&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;price&quot;&gt;UGX 2.5&lt;span class=&quot;per&quot;&gt;M&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;h5&gt;SME&lt;/h5&gt;
                    &lt;ul class=&quot;list-unstyled features&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Custom Domain&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Beautiful publishing platform &lt;span class=&quot;per-minute&quot;&gt;custom gallery settings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Responsive Website&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Search Engine Optimization&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Free hosting for 1 year&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Tech support for 1 year&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;
                      &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ray@sparkpl.ug?subject=Sparkplug SME Offer&quot; class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;Claim&lt;/a&gt;
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invite you to be a part of the celebration. These birthday bundles will run from July 21, 2015 to August 21, 2015 so don’t miss out. And don’t let your friends miss out either, share widely.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 02:11:32 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://sparkpl.ug/events/2015/07/17/celebrating-two-years/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sparkpl.ug/events/2015/07/17/celebrating-two-years/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Connected East Africa Summit 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ntf_3_at_connectedea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NTF III Project Representatives and Companies at ConnectedEA 2015&quot; title=&quot;NTF III Project Representatives and Companies at ConnectedEA 2015&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-connected-east-africa&quot;&gt;What is Connected East Africa?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summit is a brainchild of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icta.go.ke/&quot;&gt;Kenya ICT Authority&lt;/a&gt; in consultation with ICT industry players and key government decision makers. It initially started as Connected Kenya but has since grown to offer a platform in which top ICT executives in the public and private sectors in the region can network and collaborate on the use of ICT as a catalyst for service delivery to citizens. With the theme “The strength is in our networks” the objectives of the summit were to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;address gaps in ICT integration and shared infrastructure among shared infrastructure among East African member states.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;speed-up harmonization of ICT regulation across the region.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;build support on ongoing ICT integrated infrastructure projects across the East African region.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;provide a platform for meaningful networking that will result in fruitful relationships that contribute to economic development in the region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government representatives from Kenya, Uganda, Rwanda and South Sudan were present.You can see more about the summit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.connected.go.ke/connected-east-africa-2015/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-was-i-there&quot;&gt;Why was I there?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intracen.org/itc/projects/ntf-3/&quot;&gt;Netherlands Trust Fund Phase III&lt;/a&gt; (NTF III). The NTF III or Export Sector Competitiveness Programme is based on a partnership agreement between the Dutch Centre for the Promotion of Imports from developing countries (CBI), affiliated to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands, and the International Trade Centre (ITC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a sought outcome of enhancing export competitiveness of selected sectors in target developing countries, in this case Uganda and Kenya, the core objectives of the project are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;employment generation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;women and youth economic empowerment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;regional integration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;poverty reduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it did not take long to realize why the conference was the right place to be in regard to the four cornerstone objectives. The project has a huge focus on women and youth and it in manifested in the companies selected to represent Uganda at the conference. There were 3 women representatives and yours truly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natalie Kimbugwe, CEO at &lt;a href=&quot;http://bdeconsults&quot;&gt;BDE Consults&lt;/a&gt;, a company with a mission is to provide organisations, companies and individuals in East Africa with ICT Research, ICT Events, BPO Services &amp;amp; Training. They have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://expo.bdeconsults.com/&quot;&gt;Transport and Insurance Expo&lt;/a&gt; coming up in July 2015 with a theme “Technology driving safe mobility”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sherry Tumusiime, CEO at &lt;a href=&quot;http://zimbawomen.org&quot;&gt;Zimba Women&lt;/a&gt;, a project that believes in development driven by the private sector and is passionate about women-led SMEs using e-commerce as a vehicle. Now is a perfect time to get more women in STEM. Get involved and do your part. #equalitycantwait&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joanita Nnvanungi, Content Exec at &lt;a href=&quot;http://nodesix.com&quot;&gt;Node Six&lt;/a&gt;, an Internet Solutions provider. I highly recommend them for social media management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me, CEO at &lt;a href=&quot;http://sparkpl.ug&quot;&gt;Sparkplug&lt;/a&gt;, a software development firm that uses open source technology to develop web and mobile applications, integrate with client teams, design interfaces and experiences, and consult on projects large &amp;amp; small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think we represented the project, its ideals and hopes for the outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;general-observations&quot;&gt;General Observations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Governments are displaying commitment to improving regional connectivity through national backbones by promoting access and use of terrestrial cross border fibre optic networks, and exploring strategies for closing infrastructure bottlenecks. By the looks of it, it’s not all cosmetic. SEACOM recently &lt;a href=&quot;http://seacom.mu/seacom-launches-direct-presence-uganda-deployment-two-pops/&quot;&gt;launched a direct presence in Uganda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The regional industry is keen on talent pool and workforce development through ICT Innovation. There was a showcase of different technology-enabled innovations shaking up different sectors. &lt;a href=&quot;http://tmcg.co.ug/&quot;&gt;The Medical Concierge Group&lt;/a&gt; with its new take on Telemedicine. &lt;a href=&quot;http://fundibots.org/&quot;&gt;Fundi Bots&lt;/a&gt;, a robotics non-profit with aims to inspire and create a new generation of problem solvers, innovators and thinkers. &lt;a href=&quot;http://gearbox.co.ke/&quot;&gt;Gearbox&lt;/a&gt;, Kenya’s first open makerspace for design and rapid prototyping of hardware among others.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Progressive Service Delivery is a Public Private Partnership and can no longer be left to government alone. Big multinationals are partnering with government to foster development of SMEs. One really impressive outcome is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://biz4afrika.co.ke&quot;&gt;Biz4Afrika&lt;/a&gt; by conference title sponsor Microsoft Kenya. It is an online hub for Kenyan small and medium enterprises to grow their networks, and drive social development and youth employability. It does this by aggregating online solutions, freemium offers and relevant services with valuable information in one place. I really liked this one. Other initiatives like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.konzacity.go.ke/&quot;&gt;Konza Techno City&lt;/a&gt; were pretty cool too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Leadership is almost everything. Looking back, I realize now that Kenya is not too far ahead of Rwanda and Uganda. Citizens in all three countries are zealous about ICT and it’s role in development. However, that mileage is limited if the steering committee does not have a pulse on the needs of the people, the standards of technology required to fulfill them. I was quite impressed by majority of the ICT sector leaders in the different arms of government, and their willingness to listen to and empathize with their private sector colleagues. And of course the clever banter put on public display by ministers Fred Matiang’i and Jean Philbert Nsengimana of Kenya and Rwanda respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrapping-up&quot;&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, dialogue around regional integration, export competitiveness and workforce development is essential and this should only be the start of something good. I hope more conferences of this kind can be organized to engage the different stakeholders in the industry. Until next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://sparkpl.ug/events/2015/04/15/connected-eastafrica-conference-experience/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sparkpl.ug/events/2015/04/15/connected-eastafrica-conference-experience/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Designing for least astonishment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://papashabani.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/img_0634.jpg?w=774&quot; width=&quot;710&quot; alt=&quot;Papa Shabani's Beatbox Dancer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only recently, I came across a Wikipedia page talking about “The Principle of Least Astonishment”. I was quite intrigued as to what it alluded and so decided to explore the tenets of it. We shall hence forth refer to it as &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principle_of_least_astonishment&quot;&gt;POLA&lt;/a&gt;. POLA applies to user interface and software design, from the ergonomics standpoint i.e. the law or rule of freaking out your users the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the time, we are faced with systems and software that that does not match a user’s expectations or mentality, despite having seemingly skilled designers and engineers following the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clearlytech.com/2014/01/04/12-factor-apps-plain-english/&quot;&gt;12-factor app&lt;/a&gt; rules. This problem arises from a failure to design around a user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat this problem, not only in the design of software but also solutions to social challenges, we have seen the rise of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ideo.com/work/human-centered-design-toolkit/&quot;&gt;Human Centered Design&lt;/a&gt; in developing user experiences. With a user at the center of the design process, focus shifts away from user interfaces to the rhetorical situation of the information medium in development. This is the process we use to build and improve &lt;a href=&quot;http://akabbo.ug&quot;&gt;Akabbo&lt;/a&gt;, our localized crowdfunding platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used the three elements of the rhetorical situation, Audience, Purpose and Context,  to guide us. Our audience at the moment is largely Ugandan and is only getting started with online crowdfunding as a concept. Based off early user feedback, we have had to break down interfaces and borrow heavily from similar applications to which users are familiar, rather than the natural expected behavior from knowing the inner workings of the application. Since we already new the purpose of the application, our next main focus was the context. Context was a tough one as a crowd funding platform can mean different things to different people. To put it simply, context is subjective. We however decided to narrow it down to a peer to peer fundraising platform for a Ugandan audience. On locking this in, our system started to evolve to meet the need of our users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Good design is as little design as possible&lt;cite&gt;  - Dieter Rams&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides generic functions, we had to add features such as offline fundraising. A number of users wanted to meet up with campaign creators and give them cash directly as adoption of credit/debit cards is still low. This meant that we had to capture these contributions as per creators’ demands. These contributions now add previously unseen momentum to campaigns. Thanks, in a great part, to focusing around the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you focusing on users in the development of your applications? Care to share your experiences?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://sparkpl.ug/learning/2015/03/20/designing-for-least-astonishment/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sparkpl.ug/learning/2015/03/20/designing-for-least-astonishment/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Technology and the Sharing Economy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tedx_kampala.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Raymond Besiga speaking at TEDx Kampala&quot; title=&quot;Raymond Besiga speaking at TEDx Kampala 2015&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On January 9, 2015, I was honored to speak in the changemakers session at TEDx Kampala, under a theme titled “Owning Our Destiny”. As broad and cheesy a theme as they come, but it had me pondering the question of what I could possibly talk about as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://sparkpl.ug/&quot;&gt;technologist&lt;/a&gt; and change enthusiast. Something to elicit interest, fill with curiosity, suggest opportunity, and possibly trigger action long after the talk was done. Ultimately, it came down to social networks, technology, and new-age economics. All the things a twee almost-millennial could care about. And thus the title, “Technology and the sharing economy”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hUmFRwvnosc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not have all the information regarding how the sharing economy started but I believe that it had something to do with the global financial crisis, the rise of the millennials as a consumer demographic and an altruistic albeit late shift from the “this is mine” to “what is mine is yours, for a fee” economy. During the economic downturn, there was a need to minimize expenditure, optimize personal costs and create new income. The ubiquity of social networks allowed for people to trust strangers if only due to the shared hardship. Tools such as Craigslist and E-Bay were a boon to peer-to-peer transactions. Why buy a saxophone, or a tuxedo when you can rent one from a stranger online? Fantastic, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/carpool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Amazing Carpool&quot; title=&quot;Carpooling. A staple of the sharing economy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These experiences, however, are largely western. That does not mean that the sharing economy is lost on us here in Uganda and sub-Saharan Africa. Our history suggests that we have always had a sharing culture. It is happening on a small scale each day and with the right technology in place, the volume can grow. Case in point is a shared experience I had with my colleague, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mugisha.me/&quot;&gt;Moses Mugisha&lt;/a&gt;, CTO at our company &lt;a href=&quot;http://sparkpl.ug/&quot;&gt;Sparkplug&lt;/a&gt;, while on a road trip in Bushenyi District, Western Uganda. The farmers in this area do not have enough income to buy a tractor each to till their pieces of farmland. When we asked how they got about it, they intimated that it all came down to community. They formed a trust in which all the farmers contributed to a fund. Once they had accumulated enough, they time-shared a rented tractor over the course of a week for a not-so-great sum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;You are forgiven for your happiness and your successes only if you generously consent to share them&lt;cite&gt;  - Albert Camus&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was this experience that gave us the idea for our latest product, &lt;a href=&quot;http://akabbo.ug/&quot;&gt;Akabbo&lt;/a&gt;. Launched in November 2014, Akabbo, which derives it’s name from the Luganda word for a collection basket, is a localized crowdfunding platform that allows users to create campaigns and pool funds effortlessly using the far-reaching mobile money wallets. We created Akabbo to provide a venue for individuals and organizations to actualize their dreams and ideas through a shared fundraising model on a national scale. We are currently working to add international online payments processing for wider reach. You can explore the different campaigns on Akabbo &lt;a href=&quot;http://akabbo.ug/campaigns/all/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Akabbo_banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;Akabbo&quot; title=&quot;Akabbo. Localized crowdfunding made easy.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I digress but I will leave you with this: The economy of the future is people-powered and will be driven by peer-to-peer transactions. If opportunity knocks, open the door. If it does not knock, build a door.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://sparkpl.ug/talks/2015/01/27/technology-and-the-sharing-economy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sparkpl.ug/talks/2015/01/27/technology-and-the-sharing-economy/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starkey Hearing Foundation Gala Weekend</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/gala_tani_bill.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;With Tani and Bill&quot; title=&quot;Bill and Tani Austin, Founders of Starkey Hearing Foundation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 4 weeks ago, our beloved client, &lt;a href=&quot;http://starkeyhearingfoundation.org/&quot;&gt;Starkey Hearing Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, invited the directors of &lt;a href=&quot;http://sparkpl.ug&quot;&gt;Sparkplug&lt;/a&gt; to their Annual Gala. The gala is a weekend long event during which they celebrate their partnerships, ambitions, and achievements but most of all, show appreciation for the past year. It was an amazing evening of moving speeches and riveting performances, and overwhelming support for the gift of hearing by raising more than $8.7 million to reconnect families and communities around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a foundation the size of Starkey, it is very well run, with an amazing team of people who care about what they do and whom they serve. They seek to deliver the gift of hearing to those who need it most. With operations in over 45 countries worldwide, they wish to fulfill their ultimate mission that is, “So The World May Hear”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first met Bill and Tani Austin, the co-founders, while volunteering at one of their missions here in Kampala back in 2012. I liked what they did and thought to take note the next time they were in Uganda. We met again in 2013, thanks to the venerable Richard Brown, and thus begun our journey to jumpstart their International Patient Database system. It is for this reason that I, together with my colleague Moses Mugisha, were invited to join celebration of this and the many other achievements that the Starkey Hearing Foundation achieved this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish to share photos of some of my favorite moments from the gala, as well as talk a little bit about some of the interesting people I met there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/gala_honorees.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Starkey Gala Honorees&quot; title=&quot;Starkey Gala Honorees&quot; /&gt;
I got to be in the same auditorium and share and evening with these amazing people. Care to guess the names of some of the people in this photo?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/founders_circle_luncheon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Founders' Circle Luncheon&quot; title=&quot;Founders' Circle Luncheon&quot; /&gt;
Founders’ Circle Luncheon was really informative, and fulfilling as we got to see the product of our work on display, and meet Starkey partners from the different countries around the world.  And I got to chat with the former president of Malawi, H.E. Dr. Joyce Banda!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sister_rosemary.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sister Rosemary Nyirumbe&quot; title=&quot;Sister Rosemary Nyirumbe of Sewing Hope&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting Sister Rosemary Nyirumbe, a TIME 100 honoree, was one of the highlights for me as she represents the power of empathy and hope in any community. With her organization, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sewinghope.com/&quot;&gt;Sewing Hope&lt;/a&gt;, she presides over Saint Monica’s Vocational School in Gulu, Uganda and invites formerly abducted and ostracized girls, who return with LRA rebels’ children, and imparts vocational skills such as tailoring so that they may gain independence. Working together with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wpdi.org/&quot;&gt;Forest Whitaker Foundation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prosforafrica.com/&quot;&gt;Pros for Africa&lt;/a&gt;, she has been able to have great impact on this section of her community. Keep up the great work Sister Nyirumbe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rami_and_mazen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rami and Mazen&quot; title=&quot;Rami and Mazen of Parents Circle - Families Forum&quot; /&gt;
The work that Abraham Rami Elhanan and Mazen Faraj are doing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ParentsCircleFamiliesForum&quot;&gt;Parents Circle - Families Forum&lt;/a&gt; to bring about peace in the Gaza strip cannot go ignored. Glad they got awarded for their efforts. I hope and pray for peace in Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dikembe_mutombo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dikembe Mutombo&quot; title=&quot;Dikembe Mutombo of Dikembe Mutombo Foundation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, we cannot not be excited about meeting Dikembe Mutombo! He does a lot of great work with his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dmf.org/&quot;&gt;foundation&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason I wrote this post was to show appreciation for our client, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://starkeyhearingfoundation.org/&quot;&gt;Starkey Hearing Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, and highlight the importance of partnership. Choosing the right partners goes a long way in achieving impact for any cause you set out to achieve. They have a lot of great partners. Are you choosing the right partners?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://sparkpl.ug/events/2014/08/19/starkey-gala-weekend/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sparkpl.ug/events/2014/08/19/starkey-gala-weekend/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Key Takeaways from 2013</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey folks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a bit. Happy New Year! So, I thought to share a few lessons I learned from the past year, before the hype dies down and the takeaways evolve beyond the realm of 2013. They are in no specific order, and I warn you, I may rumble at times but here goes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;emerge-from-trying-circumstances-with-self-awareness-and-gratitude-for-the-lessons-learned&quot;&gt;Emerge from trying circumstances with self-awareness and gratitude for the lessons learned.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is for this reason alone that I am sharing my experiences thus far. It’s been a challenging year in which I quit my job to start &lt;a href=&quot;http://sparkpl.ug&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sparkplug&lt;/a&gt; but I have enjoyed every minute of the learning experience. The positive experiences kept me going forward, while I learned from the negative. I feel like a much better person now, which leads me to the next takeaway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Do not stall.
Always have the fear of being complacent or stagnant. If you’re no better than you were six months ago, something needs to change. Iterate, experiment and seek to make a better you. Invest time and energy in creating an optimal present and future for yourself. Needless to say, a better you translates to a happier you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Be nice.
Do not go out of your way to displease others, especially as a way of projecting an image of strength. Be kind, and fair but always speak your mind. If there’s one thing I have noticed, the most successful people, like Aamito, Beyonce, and Bill Gates to name but a few are humble, respectful but also speak honestly. It’s a karma thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Do not give up.
I cannot overstate this. It speaks for itself. Go ahead and imagine Morgan Freeman reading this out loud to you. No one who ever gave up achieved anything. Dr. Arsene Wenger did not give up after guiding his club, Arsenal FC, to eight trophyless seasons. Here’s to hoping he does not make it nine. Hehehe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Success is not final, failure is not fatal. It is the courage to continue that counts.&lt;cite&gt;Winston Churchill&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Reflect.
Be self-reflective in an accurate and productive way. Don’t get comfortable. Challenge yourself to think outside your box. Be hard on your opinions and perceptions. Polish them so that no matter what, they are mindful of others, but fully owned by you. This is one way I have learned to keep evolving myself without getting in anyone’s way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Spend time with yourself.
As it turns out, you will be surprised at how not boring you are. Its probable that you are not the most boring person you know. That said, I do not recommend a non-stop, one person party, but rather an opportunity to carve out “Heads Down” time. Rest yourself. And yes, you can be happy alone, as with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Play the long game.
If anything is worth getting into, you have to invest time, and not expect immediate results. Imagine is as a roller coaster, with all the thrills, highs and lows, in slow motion. And while you do it, celebrate the successes, learn from the failures, and enjoy growth, naturally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Keep tabs.
Keep a journal, or something like it, and write down your experiences. Be original. Don’t lie to yourself. Write about what you know, feel, see, think. It will serve as a reference when you gauge your evolution and growth at a later time. Think of it as a personal history archive, that is not Facebook. Hehehe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The investment in knowledge yields the best results&lt;cite&gt;Benjamin Franklin&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Enhance your knowledge.
Benjamin Franklin once said, “The investment in knowledge yields the best results”. He was a wise man, take his advice. Find the knowledge to fill the gaps in your skills, or feed your curiosity. In any case, you never know when that tidbit of information will win you a round of drinks at the next Trivia night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Have a code.
Set rules and follow them consistently. Not that I have anything against unrestricted freedom, I just think its better to have bounds before limitless options become your indecision prison. Specifics bring clarify. Remember this though, the rules you make are yours to follow, not set for those around you.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://sparkpl.ug/learning/2014/01/24/takeways-from-2013/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sparkpl.ug/learning/2014/01/24/takeways-from-2013/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
